good morning welcome to Saturday where I
forgot that I have 88 at 9 o'clock so we
shortened the hour to 20 minutes so I
just do an update on these dates there's
no link to join because ah so what have
I been up to this week I was doing all
of the regular the regular things
attending all of the the idea cafe the
sessions in the morning as well as of
course the together tech board meeting
yesterday and then together tech
roundtable today which is the reason
this is this is earlier I can talk
another day just not right today every
other day there's a link to join in
Twitter nor this but you can you can
type absolutely just usually there's a
link to actually call in and join on
video and today there's so I've been
updating a document on Nick it suggested
basically a document that just explains
what it is that I'm up to and where you
can find what I'm up to
and so I wrote that out and in the
middle of I'm in the middle of doing a
spreadsheet on the links to all of the
different different things I did all
look the different things this week I
did an idea cafe RIT a cafe right now
it's focusing on the five questions and
this one is we did who are my people
last week was who am i and it was I mean
we talked with where people were and
bolts Shiloh and Eric but there was
maybe a fourth person who was also there
I can't run right now
this is possibility during the pandemic
we don't actually talk about Cove it 19
we're talk about what we can create
together
gerrate our old the rest of the worlds
down time I was already on downtime the
idea Canada was who are my people which
has helped me feel very connected to the
people who were joining up for Friday
sessions were still doing coaching and a
92 coaching on relationship with self
which was illuminating because it's the
first time I've sat down with that
particular tool where you have to list
four characters like negative
characteristics
find about yourself and then for
characteristics about the four
characteristics about that you like and
partners you don't like about yourself
and honestly there it's not that I think
I'm perfect it's that I think I'm
perfect exactly as I am and so is
everybody else
and so although there are
characteristics that I would do better
without having them makes it a full it's
the combination of our traits our
challenges and our talents that make us
who we are and it's just not there's
nothing that I would get rid of because
I know that everything that I currently
have is here to serve me in exactly that
way so that was I did the coaching
yesterday on the grades page it was self
we did a solution raising on Wednesday
on package you know materials which was
good I always enjoy the solution
raisings
so now answering that's kind of like
what I did and then answering the five
questions Who am I is the first question
and my answer this week is that I
realize after writing out what I am up
to that I am and indeed doing a lot and
to truly sit with that and honor that
and be proud of it yeah but that is that
is part of who I am but that I also do
really need to go for a walk and to find
balance and take time to make my life
work in order to be able to to even do
what I have taken on let alone let alone
taking on more and that I am still
learning about Who I am and what I am
capable of during this pandemic and that
it there's new like to just bring a
remaining remaining aware vaguely ever
reason having been on pandemic I haven't
been on pandemic they change they've a
periscope depend I'm a I've had been on
periscope in a while so the people who
call in usually again there's a link and
Twitter on every other day for people to
join
and come in be on camera and talk to us
all but there isn't awaited Colleen as
I'm also on YouTube so just learning
about myself in the pandemic that
although this my life hasn't actually
changed that much besides my kid being
homeless Oh which is actually really
changed like it's my dad
currently needs a little more help than
just be unit kind with myself that I
that I'd have to take on lesson amor
that it it's okay to be where I am it's
okay to not be fixing the world 24/7
well everyone's at home and I feel like
they have the time and like are looking
for something to do and I have something
for them to do but yes that I'm still
learning about me in the pandemic who
are my people as I said we did the idea
cafe specifically on those people on
that question this week and realizing
honestly my people are absolutely
everywhere everyone who cares about
having a better lives themselves as well
as as long as it doesn't stop there as
long as you aren't what's the word I
don't even know what that you're need
for yourself actually hurts other
people's most if you're if we can do it
in an efficient open manner any time I'm
looking out for my own needs I'm also
looking out for everyone else's and so
those are my people the people who want
to improve their own lives and the lives
of other people and can see that can see
that their highest self is only
achievable when other people also have
that don't be a deterrent other terms
yeah basically don't share other people
my people are also my family that yes I
do need to in fact look after look after
my dad and that that is worthy of spoons
than it is and risk that I had to go
take the bus to go and get him his
prescription and been helping get him
food and and although I'm used to doing
that of course for my child I've it's
different it's very different but yes my
family right people
what is my purpose is the next question
and after doing the self coaching this
week very much that my what what my
purpose is right now because I'm always
going to be living my world changing
let's create a world that works for
everyone purpose is to find balance and
surrender I have surrendered nearly 100%
to my own life that I am exactly who I
meant to be to do this I know that I
have not in fact surrendered to the way
the world is because there's always the
it's just ironic it's like the more you
surrender to what is more the faster it
changes in a positive direction needed
it to change in a positive direction is
the opposite of stronger into how it is
and so the more that like it's trying
and forcing the less happens and so
balance and surrender is very much my
purpose my like personal purpose right
now just surrender to what is accept
what is and then find a path as opposed
to needing it to be a certain way and
surrendering to I can't take on more I
can do what I'm doing and constantly
answering these five questions which is
one of the things on the document that's
the five question and that yes that is
the other thing that is my purpose that
I am writing a document that I am I did
not finish notes here but I mean the
things that I have listed on there or
the together attack and what together
Tech is idea cafe which is kind of a
past future past pet project like the
project I'm concentrating on and it's
still in existence so anyway idea cafe
together Tech the solution raising the
five questions I feel like there's one
more on there but I might be wrong but
it's something all right
and then plus I mean admitting the baby
space and showing up for the Omega rural
conversations and the other things that
are are more those projects so what do I
need so why is this always such a hard
one for me so you kind of have in one
way I have everything I need I have a
roof over my head I food on the table I
have the surrender to this is happening
on its perfect time at the same time I
know that the next thing I would really
enjoy having and would really move this
forward is having a group of people who
want to
and co-create the system of co-creation
of how do we create how do we go from
problem through solution to actually
something existing in the world with
10,000 people and I have many ideas but
anything has to be generated with people
for people so having one person decide
on what a system would look like the
10,000 people is not really that great
having 510 people having a conversation
what would work for them being one of
10,000 is much more easily extrapolated
to 10,000 10,000 people I'm happy
25 50 people having that conversation is
even more better so what I need is
people who want to co-create the system
of co-creation and try and fail in in
the direction of success that is like
the purpose of life like you've never
get it perfect so there's always gonna
be room for improvement as long as
you're owning that it's about starting
being open about what's going wrong and
what's going right and then continually
improving it and so I'm looking for
other people who want to do that process
I found them for together tech or making
the tech cooperative a drone Bentley and
the meeting and other people are joining
to make like the Omni win Mehta project
of projects but the actual process of
solution raising where we're able to go
again from idea from problem through
solution to actually funding it and
creating something in the world that we
want business solution to our problems
that don't involve the government right
that is a internal solution
it was like right these it solves this
problem or moves this problem powerfully
towards a solution for those 10,000
people with $100,000 right so that is
what I'm what most need are those people
what am i ready to let go of which is
the fifth question that was added last
week because it is a powerful question
and very much needed
what am I ready to let go of and this
little weird because it's like I'm in
the process of letting go of a lot of
stuff I don't know just like these
questions if there it's ever fully
letting letting go of right it's like
I'll have a little less grip on it but
no that's okay I don't know
actually willing to like let the helium
balloon go anyway I'm ready to let go of
the certainty of how things will go and
I have continually as somebody who
needed things to be mapped out and to
know the whole big picture in order to
take the first step and then I got that
and then I got had to like all of that
go and that is exactly what needed to
happen I wouldn't have taken my first
step that was I had the whole big
picture on how we can create a world
that works for everyone
but that world that works for everyone
is a world that works for me as everyone
not one that works for everyone as
individuals in that even though it
actually does but it's like if I
communicate it it's it's recreating that
about ourselves so letting go of how it
needs to be and just constantly being in
that in that in my body like when
there's tension when there's anxiety
around this isn't going right which
happens all the time then being aware of
that and then allowing it and so letting
go of the certainty and with that
surrendering to what is surrendering to
this is the state of the world right now
and this is the state of my life right
now and everything is perfectly exactly
how it's supposed to be in order for
tomorrow to come if you sure to come and
although the what energizes me is
creating a world that works for being
which of course means changing this
world if there's a utopian vision for in
the future in mind then it's getting
there that is the point instead of the
instead of the journey and the journey
is basically always the point you never
answer these five questions fully it's
about continually answering them we
never are going to answer we're never
gonna have a utopian society we're going
to have a proto peein Society we're
gonna have we start and we continually
improve and if we starting attaining the
improved they'll never be perfect but it
will always be better every generation
every month every year will be better
than the ones before yeah guarantee
they'll never be another pandemic we
can't guarantee there will never be a
famine but when we have the win arc
Global Connections give us resiliency
instead of fragility right now our
supply chain is so fragile and complex
and done for the profit of a very tiny
minority of our population and instead
we can have the actual information that
gives us resiliency of redundancy and
resiliency of being connected with
people all over the world and having
that innovation connection
I mean if somebody comes up with an idea
anywhere in the world we can all benefit
from it is amazing I mean what currently
works right and so that is what I'm
currently letting go up that's what's
currently going on and now reading that
you need to stop and talk about copa90
what is it I don't know if Santosh is
still here but what it's it you needed
to say about cope at 19 again it's
basically impossible to call in I mean I
can put the invite up if somebody wants
to call it we go oh no we don't have 15
minutes this is in half an hour into 20
minutes here five minutes but if you
wanted to go in or wanted to come on
counter you can just do the voice but
unfortunately it doesn't work two of
them what's the word
you can't just click on it you have to
copy and paste it and since you can't
really copy and paste our to periscope
you have to like write it down and then
you let's write down the story at the
end sooner coms than that I'm down to I
mean I'm little Cove in nineteen out cuz
this open 19 he's a lot it's a lot and
it's a lot for me even though my life
hasn't changed that much
neither my life itself and or my view of
the world and yet the amount that it has
changed has been devastating is the
wrong word because that just implies
negativity but whatever the devastation
of positive and negative is together all
mixed together
it has been it has changed things even
though for me it has been less of a
dramatic change than for other people
again both for myself in my family
I used to stay home basically all the
time anyway is but the world like I can
I remember myself going through the
various times I've had like awakening in
my consciousness and it's never Pleasant
or never has been pleasant in the past
and so although right now knowing what I
need to go through I'm okay with that
knowing what everyone else has to go
through I'm not okay with because it's
hard to let go of the certainty of what
the world is it's hard to let go of your
perception of what the world is if you
thought that our medical system was like
nearly perfect if you thought that our
governments knew what the they were
doing and if you thought that the world
worked well enough I don't know how you
hold on to that in the current times and
you're you and we need humanity not to
hold on to that because we have other
things coming other things with a much
more devastating impact other things
with a much longer timeline like
environmental degradation and climate
change
having the ability to come together and
create solutions this this pandemic has
been very it's the word it's been a
incentive is not quite the right word
but incentive for many people to
collaborate for many people to create
and innovate and do but it's it's for
the next emergency right it's for okay
how do we get respirators how do we get
face masks how do we understand what
this virus is and those are all very
important things but we also need to be
doing that with climate science we need
to be doing that with healthcare in
general how do we understand what cancer
is and why it's caused we need to be
doing that we to be collaborating on
actually creating solutions for
everything because we're government's
couldn't see and they
couldn't and honestly I didn't I didn't
put money into respirator respirator
companies right knowing that the
pandemic was nearly eminent when we went
cha close down Wuhan but let people fly
out but not to other places in China it
was basically inevitable that there was
going to be a pandemic and everywhere
but China and that this was a
respiratory illness means we come you
know it happens but also it doesn't seem
like the respirators helped with
anything not the point the point is is
that even our governments could this is
a short timeline and even then we've
seen how rapidly our world has changed
in March in April and some of this could
have been foreseen and other stuff you
can't know until it unfolds right the
toilet paper shortages what the hell I
could buy buy buy but having our
governments not be able to see okay this
thing is gonna spread it kills this many
people I don't think they would have
seen that they had to shut down everyone
has like self isolate that is a big
economic changing world changing thing
but anyway everyone's concentrating on
like solving the next thing and not the
things the next next thing or the next
exact thing so everyone else is
concentrating on like how do we actually
get healthcare workers through this
which is important and I'm really glad
there's people concentrating on it but
the rest of us who don't have anything
to contribute to that really can be
concentrated on the next next I think
which is like how do we feed ourselves
how do we create a new economic system
because this one is collapsing how do we
create a world where we don't need to
rely on our governments for billion
dollars because we can see one is going
to corporations not to us a lot of it
and two if the corporations aren't set
for emergencies do you really think
they're gonna they're gonna need another
bailout in three months another bailout
in six months and so are the people and
that leads to hyperinflation and so our
current we're seeing our current economy
collapse the government the politicians
aren't going to be able to even see that
to the same degree because their entire
like the
more steeped you are in game a the more
privileged you are in game a the more
you have money and even just security of
any kind right even if you have a
minimum-wage job and you have a roof on
a roof on your head a roof over your
head food on the table it's harder to
find you're gonna see everything you
lose instead of what you gained and the
truth is working together we can gain
everything right now I'm about to go
because it's been 20 minutes but right
now I was binge watching last week the
lot of cult stuff stuff on I watched
Waco and the children of God and then
somehow it switched into there was this
like reality TV show about 24 hours in
the past and then I've been watching
this BBC drama series called the mill
from the 1800's like child labor and
women's rights and we've come a long way
and that leap forward the leap towards
children not working 12-hour days
slavery being wrong and abolishing it
and then what does that mean when it
like it's a weird I'm gonna do I'm gonna
do an entire an entire hour session
because I definitely can't cover it in
the negative one and a half minutes I
have wrong but we've come a long way and
that leap forward in in labor relations
of starting unions that's the past
starting new labor unions isn't really
gonna help us in the same way like even
watching this one you can see a lot of
the patterns repeating but consumer we
need that the labor movement we now need
the consumer movement we need to be able
to say listen I need my needs met and I
don't want the met by for-profit
corporations that are just gonna lie to
me and pollute the planet and destroy my
body if we can create everything we need
as a consumer base without needing to go
through the for-profit system we get to
save money and the planet on ourselves
and nobody can compete with that in the
external world once we we get started
worker quad this is the thing with
workers movement was very much needed
and still
but even if the entire world was worker
cooperatives we still have what we have
now we have corporations competing with
each other and lying to people because
they need the money they need the wage
they need to be able to have it to have
that to just even if it's equitably
dispersed to its workers they're still
the profit motive when you take out the
profit motive when you make the thing
the motive to make a better
transportation system better health care
system then and you don't have to when
you know your needs are met no matter
what then you can pour your heart and
soul and energy into doing what you want
to do and you don't need to lie about it
if there isn't shame and penalty
associated with mistakes and you're not
trying to pass off your mistakes in
externalities to the entire world
there's just so many things you can do
together but I can't get into all of
that for 23 minutes but I'm here
everyday at 8:30 usually till 9:30
Saturdays is the only day we do a
shorter one and together we are going to
create a world that works for everyone
and I'm going to do as much as I can
well surrendering and owning that the
pandemic makes me have less capacity to
to be able to do what I was doing before
before this hit with my kid home with
just added stress of the world and what
the world is about to go through that is
also what I'm letting go of that's
certainly right the certainty of a bad
future if we don't do what I'm proposing
because that's not certain there's tons
of people with tons of ideas out there
and I can see that it's nearly in
evitable we create a better world if we
work if we get any kind of organized if
we work together in any kind of way in
the right direction which to me is
towards cooperation towards transparency
towards any step in that direction
gives us more power it gives us more
energy gives us more information to take
the next step to take the next step and
as long as we're taking those steps
together and together being whoever
wants to be together not Carolla course
of not force in the outside world to do
what we want them to do if we start look
at what's going wrong and keep moving
there's nothing we can't do
truly and so that is what we are talking
about in what we are doing
during this hour and the better place to
war the best place to watch is on
YouTube on the channel Jubilee saves the
world by meandering through life
paradigm also on periscope and Twitter I
generally post the the comments post on
Twitter and in the description for
YouTube table to join by a stream yard
link today cuz it's 20 minutes that
doesn't happen I have to go get to a
roundtable over on the together tech
channel I will be this week completing
and then posting in every one of my
videos the link to the document that I
was talking about earlier about what I'm
up to an explanation of each of the
various projects as well as a schedule
of them so a one week here's where you
can find me and a hey here to it
together Tech is rosewood idea cafe is
here's what solutionizing is and maybe
here's what I'm looking for
which if I could articulate then I would
be able to but it's like if there's a
piece of this you're supposed to be
doing that I'm not that is your piece to
do and that is who will who will be
going on work but for right now I will
be saying goodbye and if you're on the
together tech channel I will we'll see
you in two minutes there